<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Atanas G. Iliev</title>
    <link>https://example.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Atanas G. Iliev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>atanasgiliev03@gmail.com (Atanas Iliev)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>atanasgiliev03@gmail.com (Atanas Iliev)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 10:25:59 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On New Beginnings</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 10:25:59 -0400</pubDate><author>atanasgiliev03@gmail.com (Atanas Iliev)</author>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the blog! This will be a really short piece addressing something I have always struggled with but which I hope there is still time to master.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m one of those people who begin a lot of stuff and never see them through. It is not necessarily a bad thing because at least it signals that I&amp;rsquo;m rarely bored (I abandon stuff when I find something more interesting to occupy my mind with), but it is still not ideal.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the blog! This will be a really short piece addressing something I
have always struggled with but which I hope there is still time to master.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m one of those people who begin a lot of stuff and never see them through.
It is not necessarily a bad thing because at least it signals that I&rsquo;m rarely bored
(I abandon stuff when I find something more interesting to occupy my mind with),
but it is still not ideal.</p>
<p>Throughout my conscious life, I have admired hard work and persistence in a way that
resembled jelaousy but never really as if they were a virtue. In fact, I never
like it when meritocracy is implicitly associated with hard work because I seem
to treat persistence as I would treat being blue eyed&ndash; An amazing thing that one
is born with.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m actually still convinced this is unfortunately at least partially true. After all,
we learn things by doing them repeatedly and consistencly and this is what I mean by
hard work and persistence. Hence, if there is not another way to learn things, it follows,
that being persevearing cannot be learned.</p>
<p>Then again we did invent contacts. I, thankfully, have blue eyes and, even more
gratefully, have good vision as of now. And yet it does give hope that I can become
more consistent&hellip;</p>
<p>At the end of the day, I hope I don&rsquo;t abandon this project. There are a few things
I will be incorporating to help me stay on track. No expectations. No goals.
Lots of self praise and rewards.</p>
<p>Today is the 3rd of August. I originally wanted to publish this website (and this post)
on the first, but life got in the way. I will be trying to post one post a day
for the remainder of the month though. Anyway, thanks for reading :)</p>
<p>By the way, please excuse the fact that the <strong><a href="/projects/">Projects</a></strong> and
<strong><a href="/art/">Art</a></strong> pages are unfinished as of yet. I still have to start the former
and add reflections and descriptions to the latter. In the meantime, please check the
August <strong><a href="/puzzle/">Puzzle</a></strong>!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Draw...</title>
      <link>https://example.com/art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 10:25:59 -0400</pubDate><author>atanasgiliev03@gmail.com (Atanas Iliev)</author>
      <guid>https://example.com/art/</guid>
      <description>This page documents my experience taking the Dartmouth SART 15 (Drawing I) course. I&amp;rsquo;m taking the course with basically no prior drawing experience whatsoever, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying it a lot. You can find all the pieces I&amp;rsquo;ve produced for the course below along with short assignment descriptions and reflections for each piece.&#xA;Week 1: Learning the Basics of Shading A Sphere&#xA;Week 2: Still Life Observation Pillars and Drapes</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This page documents my experience taking the Dartmouth SART 15 (Drawing I) course.
I&rsquo;m taking the course with basically no prior drawing experience whatsoever, and
I&rsquo;ve been enjoying it a lot. You can find all the pieces I&rsquo;ve produced for the
course below along with short assignment descriptions and reflections for each
piece.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="week-1-learning-the-basics-of-shading">Week 1: Learning the Basics of Shading</h3>
<p><img src="/images/sphere.png" alt="A sphere"><br>
<em>A Sphere</em></p>
<h3 id="week-2-still-life-observation">Week 2: Still Life Observation</h3>
<p><img src="/images/week2.png" alt="Still life"><br>
<em>Pillars and Drapes</em></p>
<h3 id="week-3-still-life-composition-design">Week 3: Still Life Composition Design</h3>
<p><img src="/images/week3.png" alt="First creative piece"><br>
<em>Ruddier than a Cherry</em></p>
<h3 id="weeks-4-5-live-figures-sketching--m-c-escher-inspired-piece">Weeks 4-5: Live Figures Sketching + M. C. Escher Inspired Piece</h3>
<p><img src="/images/week4.png" alt="Figure drawing"><br>
<em>Man on Black Paper</em></p>
<p><img src="/images/week5.png" alt="Escher-inspired piece"><br>
<em>Light Play</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who is behind this?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 10:25:59 -0400</pubDate><author>atanasgiliev03@gmail.com (Atanas Iliev)</author>
      <guid>https://example.com/about/</guid>
      <description>How nice to meet you!. I am a 21-years-old guy originally from Plovdiv, Bulgaria. I went to an US high school called the American College of Sofia, the first American school outside of the US :), before I crossed the pond back in August 2022 to arrive in the great state of New Hampshire. I am a Math major at Dartmouth College and I am also studying Computer Science and Classics (it is not yet clear whether any of those will become a full major or will stay a minor).</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>How nice to meet you!. I am a 21-years-old guy originally from Plovdiv, Bulgaria.
I went to an US high school called the American College of Sofia, the first American
school outside of the US :), before I crossed the pond back in August 2022 to arrive
in the great state of New Hampshire. I am a Math major at Dartmouth College and
I am also studying Computer Science and Classics (it is not yet clear whether
any of those will become a full major or will stay a minor). I am also interested in
Quantitative Finance and Philosophy, especially Philosophy of Math and Epistemology.
Some of my favorite philosophers include Plato, Descartes, and Bertrand Russell.</p>
<p>Originally, I was supposed to study Math <em>and</em> Philosophy. I took one Phil course and
I loved it. I took another and I hated it. So that&rsquo;s that (as you&rsquo;ll soon discover
determination and perseverance are not my strongest suits at all). I still love the subject
and might actually be about to do some research in it quite soon. In terms of 20th
and 21st century philosophy trends though I have a vividly strong preference for
analytic philosophy, so I&rsquo;m afraid I don&rsquo;t know a thing about many of the famous
continental folks from that period&hellip; In terms of Philosophy of Math, I am a
Platonist, and I&rsquo;m also a rationalist but more in the sense of Frege and Russell than in
the one of say Leibniz. And I definitely don&rsquo;t agree with Kant on his epistemic views.
I&rsquo;m also in the free-will camp. I&rsquo;m also a Platonist when it comes to the problem of
universals although I prefer properties to Platonic forms.</p>
<p>Back to Math, my primary focus is logic and foundations (not necessarily set theory :).
A fun story about me is that I took my culminating experience for my Math major
in my freshman winter (and I aced it!). Turned out that the Dartmouth honors logic
course satisfies the requirement but I took it out of interest, so it kinda worked out
coincidentally. I am particularly interested in <em>consistency</em> and systems that can
show their own consistency. These are usually very weak. You can&rsquo;t multiply things
most of the time. Not many practical applications either&hellip; I also like most discrete
subjects from combinatorics and probability to graph theory. I am not a fan of geometry
and topology and I prefer algebra to analysis. I do like some more applied stuff though
be it on the rare occasion. I took a two-terms sequence of courses about options trading
covering the BS equation, Ito calculus, exotic options, non-constant rates, and other stuff.</p>
<p>I started learning Ancient Greek in early 2024. I took an intensive one-term two-credits course in
my sophomore spring and am about to take another course in my junior fall. In the Spring,
we read mostly fables and some adapted snippets from Plato, Lysius, Xenophon, and others.
I also took part in an extracurricular group where we read Koine rather than Attic.
We read the entire James and moved on to read a section from Matthew (The Sermon on the Mount).
Right now (Summer 2024) I&rsquo;m reading Book 1 from the Nichomanean Ethics with a professor
outside of class just for fun. In the Fall, my class will read some unadapted Lysius and Plato.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m also a big Anglophile. Basically, you can always be at least 95% certain that I&rsquo;m
going to concur with whatever the British are doing right now. A staunch monarchist,
a Tory at heart (if not always one in practise) and a lover of everything British.
I adore English literature, from Milton to Stoppard and from Chauser to Christie
and from University Challenge to the Bake Off. Somewhat
coincidentally my favorite composer is Handel and my favorite painter is Turner (though
this one is closely contested with a German guy). I do mix up US and UK spellings though,
it just depends on the mood&hellip;</p>
<p>Some of my favorite stuff: The Harry Potter Series, <em>King Lear</em>, High Church
Anglicanism, Pokémon, <em>Arcadia</em>, Matcha-based drinks, <em>Keeping up Appearances</em>, and
many many more.</p>
<p>This blog is going to be about the many stuff I like and the many stuff I don&rsquo;t.
It will probably contain mostly short random thought pieces but I will also
try to write some longer more informative stuff from time to time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s a Riddle!</title>
      <link>https://example.com/puzzle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 10:25:59 -0400</pubDate><author>atanasgiliev03@gmail.com (Atanas Iliev)</author>
      <guid>https://example.com/puzzle/</guid>
      <description>On this page you can find a puzzle of my devising. I will update this section every month provided the current puzzle has been solved, and I will post the name of everyone who has submitted a correct solution. The solutions to previous puzzles will be found in the Blog archive. In case there is a question at the end of a given puzzle, it is not necessary that the an answer to that question is the answer to the puzzle.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>On this page you can find a puzzle of my devising. I will update this section</em>
<em>every month provided the current puzzle has been solved, and I will post the</em>
<em>name of everyone who has submitted a correct solution. The solutions to previous</em>
<em>puzzles will be found in the <strong><a href="/posts/">Blog</a></strong> archive. In case there is a question at the</em>
<em>end of a given puzzle, it is not necessary that the an answer to that question</em>
<em>is the answer to the puzzle.</em></p>
<p><em>You can email me your submissions :D</em></p>
<hr>
<p><strong>August 2024 Puzzle:</strong></p>
<p>Three Germans and a Brit meet in a hotel. It&rsquo;s huge. A German owns it. He hands them
a menu, and they decide to try one of the dishes. One of them has been trying to make it
since before this establishment existed. The English* found it tastes bad because of
the fifth ingredient in his recipe. Then again, he takes so long to explain things
(just ask the Austrian chap when you see him if you don&rsquo;t believe me). They wait as some
other dishes get prepared. The youngest one gets angry and tears the menu. No wonder
if he starves himself to death. What&rsquo;s the name of the second youngest&rsquo;s godfather?</p>
<p><em>(The answer to this puzzle is three words.)</em></p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Correct Solutions Submitted by:</strong></p>
<p>No one yet&hellip;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Am Currently...</title>
      <link>https://example.com/currently/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 10:25:59 -0400</pubDate><author>atanasgiliev03@gmail.com (Atanas Iliev)</author>
      <guid>https://example.com/currently/</guid>
      <description>Reading:&#xA;Our Town by Thornton Wilder&#xA;Ἠθικὰ Νικομάχεια βιβλίον A by Aristotle&#xA;The Iliad by Homer, translated by Alexander Pope&#xA;Novum Testamentum Graece, Nestle-Aland, 28th edition&#xA;The Book of Common Prayer, 1979 edition&#xA;Watching:&#xA;Keeping up Appearances S2&#xA;Listening to:&#xA;Handel&#xA;Taylor Swift&#xA;Vivaldi&#xA;George Gershwin&#xA;Coldplay&#xA;Studying:&#xA;Principles of Programming Languages&#xA;Probability&#xA;The Solar System&#xA;Drawing&#xA;Into:&#xA;Wedgwood Teasets&#xA;Matcha Drinks&#xA;History of Anglicanism&#xA;NYT Connections Game&#xA;Drawing:&#xA;A Self-Portrait</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Reading:</strong><br>
<em>Our Town</em> by Thornton Wilder<br>
<em>Ἠθικὰ Νικομάχεια βιβλίον A</em> by Aristotle<br>
<em>The Iliad</em> by Homer, translated by Alexander Pope<br>
<em>Novum Testamentum Graece</em>, Nestle-Aland, 28th edition<br>
<em>The Book of Common Prayer</em>, 1979 edition</p>
<p><strong>Watching:</strong><br>
<em>Keeping up Appearances</em> S2</p>
<p><strong>Listening to:</strong><br>
Handel<br>
Taylor Swift<br>
Vivaldi<br>
George Gershwin<br>
Coldplay</p>
<p><strong>Studying:</strong><br>
Principles of Programming Languages<br>
Probability<br>
The Solar System<br>
Drawing</p>
<p><strong>Into:</strong><br>
Wedgwood Teasets<br>
Matcha Drinks<br>
History of Anglicanism<br>
NYT Connections Game</p>
<p><strong>Drawing:</strong><br>
A Self-Portrait</p>
<p><strong>Enjoying:</strong><br>
<em>Acis and Galatea</em> by Handel<br>
Different Works by J. M. W. Turner</p>
<p><strong>About to Visit:</strong><br>
NYC</p>
<p><strong>Later:</strong><br>
<em>Tower of God</em> S2<br>
<em>Industry</em> S3<br>
<em>On Beauty</em> by Zadie Smith<br>
<em>Ash Wednesday</em> by T. S. Eliot<br>
<em>Rosencrantz and Guildenstern Are Dead</em> by Tom Stoppard<br>
<em>ὑπὲρ τοῦ Ἐρατοσθένους φόνου ἀπολογία</em> by Lysias</p>
<p><strong>Applying for an Internship&hellip;</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
