<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Atanas G. Iliev</title>
    <link>https://example.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Atanas G. Iliev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>atanasgiliev03@gmail.com (Atanas Iliev)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>atanasgiliev03@gmail.com (Atanas Iliev)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 10:25:59 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On New Beginnings</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 10:25:59 -0400</pubDate><author>atanasgiliev03@gmail.com (Atanas Iliev)</author>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the blog! This will be a really short piece addressing something I have always struggled with but which I hope there is still time to master.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m one of those people who begin a lot of stuff and never see them through. It is not necessarily a bad thing because at least it signals that I&amp;rsquo;m rarely bored (I abandon stuff when I find something more interesting to occupy my mind with), but it is still not ideal.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the blog! This will be a really short piece addressing something I
have always struggled with but which I hope there is still time to master.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m one of those people who begin a lot of stuff and never see them through.
It is not necessarily a bad thing because at least it signals that I&rsquo;m rarely bored
(I abandon stuff when I find something more interesting to occupy my mind with),
but it is still not ideal.</p>
<p>Throughout my conscious life, I have admired hard work and persistence in a way that
resembled jelaousy but never really as if they were a virtue. In fact, I never
like it when meritocracy is implicitly associated with hard work because I seem
to treat persistence as I would treat being blue eyed&ndash; An amazing thing that one
is born with.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m actually still convinced this is unfortunately at least partially true. After all,
we learn things by doing them repeatedly and consistencly and this is what I mean by
hard work and persistence. Hence, if there is not another way to learn things, it follows,
that being persevearing cannot be learned.</p>
<p>Then again we did invent contacts. I, thankfully, have blue eyes and, even more
gratefully, have good vision as of now. And yet it does give hope that I can become
more consistent&hellip;</p>
<p>At the end of the day, I hope I don&rsquo;t abandon this project. There are a few things
I will be incorporating to help me stay on track. No expectations. No goals.
Lots of self praise and rewards.</p>
<p>Today is the 3rd of August. I originally wanted to publish this website (and this post)
on the first, but life got in the way. I will be trying to post one post a day
for the remainder of the month though. Anyway, thanks for reading :)</p>
<p>By the way, please excuse the fact that the <strong><a href="/projects/">Projects</a></strong> and
<strong><a href="/art/">Art</a></strong> pages are unfinished as of yet. I still have to start the former
and add reflections and descriptions to the latter. In the meantime, please check the
August <strong><a href="/puzzle/">Puzzle</a></strong>!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
